Mss.Ms.Coll.137
American Philosophical Society
- I. Correspondence, 1949-2005; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 1-7)
  - Bunker, John P., 1976-2002; 3.0 folders (Box 2)
    - Folder 1, 1976-1980 (Box 2)
    - Folder 2, 1986-1994 (Box 2)
    - Folder 3, 1994-2002 (Box 2)
  - Carlson, Gary, 1966 (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Mellon University, Bulk, 1973-1974; 1973-2003 (Box 2)
  - Chalmers, Iain, 2000-2003 (Box 2)
  - Child, Charles G., 1971 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Alexander L., 1969 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Linda M., Circa 1986 (Box 2)
  - Cliff, Norman, 1960-1968 (Box 2)
  - Cochran, Betty (Mrs. William Cochran), 1981 (Box 2)
  - Contributors to A Statistical Model, 1991 (Box 2)
  - Cook, Tom, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Curran, Bill, 1986 (Box 2)
  - Danford, M. Bryan, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Davis, James A., 1981 (Box 2)
  - de Moya, Dorothy, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Dempster, Arthur, 1974-1985 (Box 2)
  - Diaconis, Persi, 1982-2000 (Box 2)
  - Dickey, Barbara, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Educational Researcher, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Efron, Bradley, 1981 (Box 2)
  - Ellegard, Alvar, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Emerson, John, 1983-2005 (Box 2)
  - Entwisle, Doris, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Evan, William M., 1964 (Box 2)
  - Eves, Howard, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Evidence-Based Policies and Indicators Systems Conference, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Fairley, Irene, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Fienberg, Stephen, 1983 (Box 2)
  - Finckenaur, Jim, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Fogg, Dr., n.d. (Box 2)
  - Friedman, Milton, 1976 (Box 2)
  - Gardner, John W., 1969 (Box 2)
  - Gaudiani, Claire L., 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - Ghurye, Sudhish G., 1956 (Box 2)
  - Gilbert, John, 1972-1975 (Box 2)
  - Goldsmith, C. H., 1989 (Box 3)
  - Goodall, Colin, 1988-1992 (Box 3)
  - Goroff, Daniel L., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Govindarajulu, Z., 1970 (Box 3)
  - Grace, Martha P., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Greenberg, B. G., 1955-1956 (Box 3)
  - Grimshaw, Jeremy, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Halvorsen, Katherine Taylor, 1982-1992 (Box 3)
  - Harding, Alan, 1969-1978 (Box 3)
  - Hartigan, John, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Harvard Community Health Plan, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Harvard University. Department of Statistics, 1974-2005 (Box 3)
  - Healy, M. J. R., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Hedley-Whyte, John, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Helfand, Mark, 1996 (Box 3)
  - Herzberg, Agnes M., 1987-1992 (Box 3)
  - Herzlinger, Regina, 1987 (Box 3)
  - Hiatt, Howard, 1974-2003 (Box 3)
  - Hirano, Shigeo, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Hoaglin, David C., 1987-2002 (Box 3)
  - Homans, George C., 1981 (Box 3)
  - Hotelling, Harold, n.d. (Box 3)
  - Howe, Eunice, 1981 (Box 3)
  - Hunt, Richard M., 1991 (Box 3)
  - International Society of Technology Assessment in Health Care, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Izzo, Luisa and Herb, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Jencks, Christopher, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Jobs offered, 1950-1956; 2.0 folders (Box 3)
  - Jones, Kenneth J., 1966-1968 (Box 3)
  - Journal of the American Statistical Association, 1952 (Box 3)
  - Kaptchuck, T. J., 1999 (Box 3)
    Bucknam McPeek.
  - Kass, Edward H., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Kessen, William, 1980-1981 (Box 3)
  - Keyfitz, Nathan, 1998-1999 (Box 3)
  - Kim, James, 2000-2003 (Box 4)
    See also Series II, Summer School Study.
  - Kinzer, David M., n.d. (Box 4)
  - Kish, Leslie, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Kjetsaa, Geir, 1983-1984 (Box 4)
  - Klitgaard, Robert, 1980-2001 (Box 4)
  - Kong, Augustine, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Kranes, Dr., 1967 (Box 4)
  - Kruskal, William, 1952-1981 (Box 4)
  - Laird, Nan, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - Larkey, Patrick, 1991-1998 (Box 4)
    Golf.
  - Larntz, Kinley, 1995 (Box 4)
  - Lasagna, Louis, 1986 (Box 4)
  - Lau, James, 1997 (Box 4)
  - Lave, Lester B., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Lebergott, Stanley, 1970-1983 (Box 4)
  - Lehmann, Erich, 1981-1990 (Box 4)
    See also: Coincidences, Series II
  - Levin, David, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Lewis, David, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Light, Richard, 1974-2001; 2.0 folders (Box 4)
    Stoto, Michael
    - Folder 1, 1974-1985 (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1985-2001 (Box 4)
  - Linnik, Yuri, 1969-1970 (Box 4)
    Russian edition of Fifty Challenging Problems in Probabliity.
  - MacMillan, Mark, 2001 (Box 4)
  - MacMillan Publishing Company, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
  - Madansky, Albert, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Mallows, Colin, 1983 (Box 4)
  - Mariner, Wendy, 1987 (Box 4)
  - Marks, Harry, 1983-1988; 2.0 folders (Box 4)
    See also: Bias, Series II.
    - Folder 1, 1983-1985 (Box 4)
    - Folder 2, 1986-1988 (Box 4)
  - McKenzie, Lionel, 1992 (Box 4)
  - McNeil, Barbara, 1992 (Box 4)
  - McPeek, Bucknam, 1989 (Box 4)
  - Meier, Paul, 1970-1975 (Box 4)
  - Mellon Foundation, 1998-2003 (Box 4)
    Chalmers, Iain Emerson, John Petrosino, Anthony
  - Merriam, Thomas, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Miech, Edward, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
  - Milamed, Debra, 2004 (Box 4)
  - Miller Report, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
  - Mood, Alexander M., 1986 (Box 4)
  - Morrison, Donald G., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Moses, Jim, 1982 (Box 4)
  - Moses, Lincoln, 1967-2005; 12.0 folders (Box 5)
    - Folder 1, 1967-1984 (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1985-1986 (Box 5)
    - Folder 3, 1987 (Box 5)
    - Folder 4, 1988 (Box 5)
    - Folder 5, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Folder 6, 1990-1991 (Box 5)
    - Folder 7, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Folder 8, 1994-1996 (Box 5)
    - Folder 9, 1997 (Box 5)
    - Folder 10, 1998 (Box 5)
    - Folder 11, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Folder 12, 2000-2005 (Box 5)
  - Moynihan, Daniel Patrick, 1972-1990; 2.0 folders (Box 5)
    - Folder 1, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Folder 2, 1975-1990 (Box 5)
  - Nathan, David G., 1987 (Box 5)
  - National Academy of Education, 2005 (Box 5)
  - National Academy of Sciences, 1978 (Box 5)
  - Nelkin, Dorothy, 1984 (Box 5)
  - New England Journal of Medicine, 1997 (Box 5)
  - New England Medical Center, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Oliver, Ann, 1987 (Box 5)
  - [Olivo, Jaylyn], 1987 (Box 5)
  - Olmstead, Paul, 1981 (Box 5)
  - Penney, David E., 1988 (Box 6)
    See also: Memorandum NS-681
  - Peterson, Paul, 1997-2003 (Box 6)
  - Petrosino, Anthony, 2000-2005 (Box 6)
    Includes biography of Mosteller.
  - Portnoy, Stephen, 1983-1984 (Box 6)
  - Pratt, John W., 1989 (Box 6)
  - President's Commission on Federal Statistics, 1971 (Box 6)
    Two letters mentioning meeting with President Nixon.
    See also: Wallis, W. Allen
  - Price, Don K., 1974 (Box 6)
  - Purcell, Edward M., 1953 (Box 6)
  - Pusey, Nathan M., 1970 (Box 6)
  - Quality of Life Conference. Sintra, Portugal, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Raiffa, Howard, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Reagan, Timothy, 1987-1988 (Box 6)
  - Reibel, Dale, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Relman, Arnold, 1992 (Box 6)
  - Reynolds, Hobart, 2004 (Box 6)
  - Rice, Dorothy P., 1978 (Box 6)
  - Riecken, Henry, 1968 (Box 6)
  - Robbins, Laura A., 1987 (Box 6)
  - Roberts, Harry V., 1952 (Box 6)
  - Rosenkrantz, Bob, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Rosovsky, Henry, 1975-1982 (Box 6)
  - Royal Statistical Society, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
    Freeman, P. R.
  - Sachs, Jason, 1997-2000; 2.0 folders (Box 6)
    - Folder 1, 1997-2000 (Box 6)
    - Folder 2, 2000 (Box 6)
  - Russell Sage Foundation, 1968-1997 (Box 6)
  - Sarndal, Carl E., 1983 (Box 6)
  - Schelling, Thomas C., 1975 (Box 6)
  - Schenley High School, 1984 (Box 6)
  - Schweiker, Robert F., 1969 (Box 6)
  - Sechrest, Lee, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Seeley, Samuel, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Shadish, William, 2002 (Box 6)
  - Sibley, Elbridge, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Singer, Burton, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Arthur P. Sloan Foundation, 1980-1982 (Box 6)
  - Smith, Marshall S., 1989 (Box 6)
  - Springer-Verlag Publishers, 1982-1984 (Box 6)
    See also: David Wallace
  - Starfield, Barbara, 1987 (Box 6)
  - Starke, E. P., 1949, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Stengle, James M., 1984-1987 (Box 6)
  - Stigler, Stephen, 1983-2002 (Box 6)
  - Stoto, Michael, 1985 (Box 6)
    See also: Richard Light
  - Straf, Miron L., 1988-2004 (Box 7)
  - Strenio, Judith, 1986 (Box 7)
  - Sultan, Betty, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Summers, Lawrence H., 2001 (Box 7)
  - Taeuber, Conrad, 1992 (Box 7)
  - Tanur, Judith, 1969-2003 (Box 7)
  - Teichroew, D., 1954, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Tenenbein, Aaron, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Thurman, Steve, 1987 (Box 7)
  - Tosteson, Daniel, 1981-1987 (Box 7)
  - Tukey, John W., 1960-1982 (Box 7)
  - Ulrich, Rich, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Unidentified Correspondents, 1971-2005 (Box 7)
  - United States Department of Labor. Bureau of Labor Statistics, 1986-1987 (Box 7)
  - Vogt, Nan (Mrs. Evon Vogt), 2004 (Box 7)
  - Wainer, Howard, 2000 (Box 7)
  - Wallace, David L., 1982-1989; 2.0 folders (Box 7)
    See also: Springer-Verlag Publishers
    - Folder 1, 1982-1983 (Box 7)
    - Folder 2, 1983-1989 (Box 7)
  - Wallis, W. Allen, 1952-1971 (Box 7)
    Includes information concerning the President's Commission on Federal Statistics and a discussion of Mosteller's meeting with President Nixon in December 1971.
    See also, Series II: World Series.
  - Walsh, John, 1990 (Box 7)
    Truman/Dewey election.
  - Weinreb, Lloyd, 1977, n.d. (Box 7)
  - Weiss, Carol H., 2000 (Box 7)
  - Wennberg, John E., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Wenner, Evelyn W., 1962-1963 (Box 7)
  - Wesleyan University (Connecticut), 1983 (Box 7)
  - West, Sandra A., 1986 (Box 7)
  - Wheeler, Stanton, 1977-1981 (Box 7)
  - Williams, Frederick W., 1969 (Box 7)
  - Willard, Ms., 1993 (Box 7)
  - Wilson, Ramon Robert ("Red Turtle"), n.d. (Box 7)
  - Wollman, Harry, 1978 (Box 7)
  - Worcester, Jane, 1977 (Box 7)
  - Wortman, Paul M., 1987 (Box 7)
  - Wright, Lori Houghton, 2005 (Box 7)
  - Yale University, 1981 (Box 7)
  - Youtz, Cleo, 1968-1998 (Box 7)
  - Zuckerman, Harriet, 1981-2004 (Box 7)
- II. Subject Files, 1947-2002; 3.5 Linear feet (Box 7-14)
  - Annual Activity Report, 2001-2002 (Box 7)
  - Annual Reports, Department of Social Relations, 1950-1958 (Box 7)
  - Autobiography, 1988-1990; 19.0 folders (Box 7-8)
    Manuscript version. Much of this material was printed after Mosteller's death as The Pleasure of Statistics: The Autobiography of Frederick Mosteller (Springer: 2010), edited by Stephen E. Fienberg, David C. Hoaglin, and Judith M. Tanur.
    - 0. Notes, 1988-1990 (Box 7)
    - 1. Pre-election Polls of 1948, 1989 (Box 7)
    - 2. Kinsey Report, 1989 (Box 7)
    - 3. Learning Theory, 1989-1990 (Box 7)
    - 4. Federalist, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 5. Halothane, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 6. Coleman Report, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 7. Childhood, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 8. Secondary School, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 9. College, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 10. Graduate Schools, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 11. Magic, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 12. Beginning Research, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 14. Coming to Harvard, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 16. Evaluation, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 17. Teaching, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 18. Group Writing, 1989 (Box 8)
    - 19. The Cape, 1989 (Box 8)
    - Right after World War II, 1989 (Box 8)
      Manuscript version of chapter which appeared in The Pleasures of Statistics as Chapter 13, "Completing the Doctorate."
  - Bayesian Analysis, 1976-1983 (Box 8)
  - Bias, 1985-2001; 9.0 folders (Box 8-9)
    See also, Series I: Marks, Harry
  - Bibliography of Critical Reviews of Clinical Trials in the Medical Literature, Circa 1978 (Box 9)
  - Biostatistics in Clinical Medicine, 1985 (Box 9)
    Contains materials relating to the second edition of Biostatistics in Clinical Medicine.
    See also: MacMillan Publishing Company correspondence, Series I.
  - Buehler, John, 1999-2000 (Box 9)
  - Calculations from Meta-Analysis in Social Research (1981), n.d. (Box 9)
  - Center for Evaluation - Papers in Progress, 2002 (Box 9)
    Miech, Edward
    Nave, Bill
  - Chapter 27, 1993-1994; 2.0 folders (Box 9)
  - Charter Schools, 2001-2004; 7.0 folders (Box 9-10)
  - Coincidences, 1985-1990 (Box 10)
    See also, Series I: Lehmann, Erich; Tanur, Judith
  - Computer-Aided Literary and Linguistic Research, 1983 (Box 10)
  - CONSORT Statement, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Contributions of Statistics, 1966-1971 (Box 10)
    See also, Series I: Kruskal, William; Moses, Lincoln; Tanur, Judith
  - Data, n.d. (Box 10)
    Numerous pages of material from same work, containing tables of random and fixed effects.
  - Delta Method, n.d. (Box 10)
  - Dice Rolling Machine, 2001 (Box 10)
  - Dirty edges - Use as evidence...of wear and tear, 1955 (Box 10)
  - Education, 1993-1994; 5.0 folders (Box 10)
    - 1. Notes on Walberg, 1994 (Box 10)
    - 2. Survey - Important Variables & 3. What Works?, Circa 1993-1994 (Box 10)
    - 4. AAAS Conference Notes and Presentation Response Sheets, 1994 (Box 10)
    - 5. Ability Grouping, 1994 (Box 10)
    - 6. Reading Notes, 1994 (Box 10)
      Includes notes written by Richard Light and Jason Sachs.
  - Education Bibliography, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Final Report - Educational Studies, n.d. (Box 11)
    Notes. Folder title is original title.
  - Fisher, R. A., 1990 (Box 11)
  - Fraud, 1980-1983; 4.0 folders (Box 11)
    A Health Science Policy seminar concerning fraud in scientific research. Includes notes, correspondence, newspaper clippings, and journal articles. Working with Frederick Mosteller were: Penelope Greene, Wendy Horwitz, and Jane Durch.
  - General Field of Statistics (Methodology), 1955 (Box 11)
  - Golf Memos, 1986-1991; 2.0 folders (Box 11)
  - Harvard Community Health Plan, Circa 1985; 2.0 folders (Box 11)
  - Harvard School of Public Health. Technology Assessment Group, 1989-2002; 2.0 folders (Box 11)
  - Interviews with Frederick Mosteller, 1979-1995 (Box 11)
  - Learning What Works - Evaluating Complex Social Interventions, 1997-1998 (Box 12)
    Annotated report from a Brookings Institution symposium along with notes.
  - Lord's Paradox, 1967, n.d.; Lord, Frederic M., 1912-2000 (Box 12)
    Reprint of Lord's "A Paradox in the Interpretation of Group Comparisons" from Psychological Bulletin(1967), Vol. 68, No. 5, and chapter from unidentified work entitled "Lord's Paradox."
  - Mathematics Steering Committee, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    Includes materials concerning a mathematics conference in Accra, Ghana.
  - Meta-Analysis Group, 1985-1986; 2.0 folders (Box 12)
  - Methods of Education Research, 2000; 2.0 folders (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Mosteller, Frederick, 1977-1996 (Box 12)
    Assorted works about Mosteller.
  - Names, 1957-1989 (Box 12)
    LIsts of names presumably compiled by Mosteller in preparation for work on his autobiography. Also includes lists of PhD degrees awarded at Harvard.
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1969-1999 (Box 12)
  - Order Statistics, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Photographs (Box 12)
  - Preliminary Results for Selected Analyses, n.d. (Box 12)
    Meta-Analysis of data concerning education and race.
  - Primary Care, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Probability Data, n.d.; 2.0 folders (Box 12)
    Includes two 5.25 inch floppy disks
  - Probability Project Memos, 1988 (Box 12)
  - Problem 341B - Wizard and the Election, Circa 1957-1958 (Box 13)
  - Problems, 1981, n.d. (Box 13)
    Statistical problems, raw calculations, exercises.
  - Problems and Solutions, American Mathematical Monthly, 1964 (Box 13)
  - Problems We Should Solve, 1964-1970, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Professional Development, 1997; 2.0 folders (Box 13)
  - Providence Measles Data (Box 13)
  - Pseudo Primes, 1991; 2.0 folders (Box 13)
  - Puerto Rican Enrollment Data, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Questions and Answers, from The American Statistician, 1947-1951 (Box 13)
  - Research Design, n.d. (Box 13)
  - Runaways, 1997 (Box 13)
  - School Vouchers, 2000-2003 (Box 13)
  - Seminar on Effective and Affordable Care, 1996-1997 (Box 13)
    Concerns healthcare. See also, Series I: Bunker, John P.
  - SGEDA Contents - Statistician's Guide Memos, 1977-1983 (Box 13)
    Bibliographic list
  - Simon, Herbert A., 2002 (Box 13)
  - Sports Notebook, Circa 1960-2000; 4.0 folders (Box 14)
  - Statistics 285 Syllabus - Large-Scale Statistical Investigations, n.d. (Box 14)
  - Summer School Study, 2002 (Box 14)
  - Teaching Models, 1997-1998 (Box 14)
  - Teaching Performance, 1997 (Box 14)
    Mieck, Edward
  - Three-Place Tables of the Binomial Distribution, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Unique Case, 1979-1983; 2.0 folders (Box 14)
    Kruskal, William
    Moses, Lincoln
    Ware, James
  - Unique Case - Single Patient, 1980 (Box 14)
  - University of Alberta, 1979 (Box 14)
  - Why Statistics is Important, 1964 (Box 14)
  - World Series, 1952-1964; 2.0 folders (Box 14)
    Wallis, W. Allen
  - Zelen, Marvin, 1990 (Box 14)
- III. Works by Mosteller, 1941-2004; 4.5 Linear feet (Box 15-23)
  In cataloging his works, Mosteller numbered each work in the order it was written. A number associated with a record reflects this chronological order.
  - 38 US Tour Golf Tournaments in 1986, 1991; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 15)
  - 1986 US Four-Round Golf Tournaments: Positions of Winners after Three Rounds, 1987; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 15)
  - 20,000 Article Problem: How a Structured Abstract Can Help Practitioners Sort Out Education Research, 2004; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 15)
    Correspondence and manuscript drafts
  - Accomplishments of the NSF Project: Basic and Applied Studies of Social Statistical Methods, 1987; Hoaglin, David C. (David Caster), 1944-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Allocating Loss of Precision in the Sample Mean to Wrong Weights and Redundancy in Sampling with Replacement from a Finite Population, 182; Hodges, J. L., (Joseph Lawson), 1922-2000; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Youtz, Cleo (Box 15)
    Manuscript draft, correspondence, and reprint.
  - Approaches to Juvenile Substance Abuse in and out of the Juvenile Justice System, 2001; Falotico-Taylor, Jennifer; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
    Manuscript
  - Assessing Agreement Between Two Measures of Clinical Efficacy, 2000; Buehler, John H.; Moses, Lincoln E.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Assessing the Effectiveness of Ambulatory Cardiac Monitoring for Specific Clinical Indications, 1992; Adams, Miriam E.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 15)
    Manuscript draft for paper printed in International Journal of Technology Assessment in Health Care, Vol. 9, No. 1
  - Assessing Institutional Quality of Care, n.d.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Assessing Social Innovations: An Empirical Base for Policy, 1974-1978; 119, 122, 128, 133; 3.0 folders; Gilbert, John P.; Light, Richard J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
    From Zeckhauser et al (eds.), Benefit-Cost and Policy Analysis 1974; Evaluation and Experiment: Some Critical Issues in Assessing Social Programs; "How Well Do Social Innovations Work?," from Tanur et al (eds.), Statistics: A Guide to the Unknown, 2nd ed.; and, Fairley and Mosteller (eds.), Statistics and Public Policy
  - Assessing Unknown Numbers: Order of Magnitude Estimation, 1977; 134; Adams, Miriam E.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 15)
    From Fairley and Mosteller (eds.), Statistics and Public Policy
    Antczak-Bouckoms, Alexia Anne; Chalmers, Thomas C., (Thomas Clark), 1917-1995; Frazier, Howard S.; Lau, Joseph; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006
  - Assigned Shares in Compensation for Radiation-Related Cancers, 1985-1986; 209-210; 2.0 folders; Lagakos, Stephen W.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
    Risk Analysis, Vol. 6, No. 3. Article, manuscript drafts, comments, and response.
  - Assigned Shares: Probability of Radiation as a Cause of Cancer, 1985; 196; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
    Abstract of talk. From Final Report, ASA Conference on Radiation and Health
  - Athletics and Academics at Selective Colleges: Researching the Game, 2003; Emerson, John D.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Benefits of Contemporary Medicine: Contributions of Lenses to Visual Health, 1992; Marks, Georgiana; McPherson, Marie A.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Wyshak, Grace (Box 15)
  - Benefits of Medicine. Chapter 2, 1993; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Bias in the Absence of a Standard, 1987; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 15)
  - Bibliography and Curriculum Vitae, 1997; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
  - Biography of John W. Tukey, 1984; 190; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    From Brillinger (ed.), The Collected Works of John W. Tukey, Vol. I
  - Book Reviews, 1945-1991; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
  - Broadening the Scope of Statistics and Statistical Education, 1987; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    Pfizer Lecture, Storrs, Connecticut, May 11, 1987.
  - Can You Be a Successful Gambler?, 1961; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    TV Guide, Vol. 9, No. 19
  - Case for Smaller Classes, 1999; 345; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    Harvard Magazine, May/June 1999.
  - Catalogue Survey of College Mathematics Courses, 1961; Choi, Keewhan; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Sedransk, Joseph (Box 16)
    Report from the Committee on the Undergraduate Program in Mathematics, Mathematics Association of America
  - Celebration in Honor of Frederick Mosteller on the Occasion of His 80th Birthday, 1996; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    Annotated program and typed speech.
  - Census, Circa 1966; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
  - Chairman's Introduction, 1973; 112; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    From Lennart Rade (ed.), Statistics at the School Level
  - Changing Role of the Statistician: Getting into the Mainstream with Policy Decisions, 1982-1983; 185; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 16)
    American Public Health Assoction Section Newsletter, Statistics
  - Chapter 7. Chi-Square Combination, 1982-1986; 4.0 folders; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 16)
    Rough manuscript drafts and notes labeled "Chapter 7, First Volume," largely concerning Chi-Square combination.
  - Chapter 9. A Look at the Mathematical Infrastructure, 1986-1987; 3.0 folders; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 16)
  - Characterizing Education Research in the 1990s: Frequency of Methodologies Used, 1999-2001; 3.0 folders; Miech, Edward J.; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Nave, Bill (Box 16-17)
    Notes, correspondence, and manuscript drafts
  - Chlorination, Chlorination By-products, and Cancer: A Meta-Analysis, 1992; Audet, Anne-Marie; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006, et al (Box 17)
    Manuscript draft of paper published in the American Journal of Public Health, Vol. 82, No. 7
    Chalmers, Thomas C., (Thomas Clark), 1917-1995; Morris, Robert D., 1956-
  - Clinical Trials, 1998; 334; McKneally, Martin F.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Neugebauer, E. A. M. (Box 17)
    From H. Troidl et al (eds.), Surgical Research: Basic Principles and Clinical Practice, Third Edition
  - Clinical Trials Methodology, 1979; 159; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    From Dossetor (ed.), Medical Advances through Clinical Trials: A Symposium on Design and Ethics of Human Experimentation
  - Clinician's Responsibility for the Decision Process, 1980; 152; Gilbert, John P.; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Center for the Analysis of Health Practices News Letter, Vol. 4, No. 1
  - Cinician's Role in Developing Measures for Quality of Life in Cardiovascular Disease, 1985; 201; McPeek, Bucknam, 1933-; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; O'Young, Judy (Box 17)
  - Collegiate Football Scores, USA, 1969-1977; 81, 139; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    Manuscript and reprint, Journal of the American Statistical Association, Vol. 65. Revised edition from Ladany and Machol (eds.), Optimal Strategies in Sports
  - Combination of Results of Stated Precision: I. The Optimistic Case, 1982; 180; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006; Tukey, John W., (John Wilder), 1915-2000 (Box 17)
    Drafts and reprint from Utilitas Mathematica, Vol. 21a
  - Comments on Models for Learning Theory, 1953; 29a; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)
    From Symposium on Psychology of Learning Basic to Military Training Problems
  - Community Reactions to the Concorde: An Assessment of the Trial Period at Dulles Airport, 1977; 129; Mosteller, Frederick, 1916-2006 (Box 17)